# Shivani Giri

#### Software Developer

Infrastructure Engineer with 4+ years of working experience who loves to solve engineering problems. Well-versed in writing code to architecting solutions & strategies. Always prefer following DevOps pratices using open-source softwares with a passion to contribute back to community.



#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2018

### SAP Labs, Bangalore, India

Site Reliability Engineer (May 2020 - Present)

SAP Cloud Platform is a region specific PaaS solution. It's maintained by multiple teams in a single Infrastructure as code repository

- · Resolved production issues e.g. Memory Leak, Slow DB writes, etc
- · Automated rotation of AWS IAM user key after 90 days via Terraform & CD
- Achieved High availability by rearchitecting stack for multi-zone deployment with Load Balancer provisioned via Terraform
- Reduced downtime by 75% by introducing automated RCA scripts in CI/CD pipeline which can be triggered during outages
- Eliminated toil by automating landscape update process via shell scripting which made it 85% faster and error free
- Implemented Mutual TLS to authenticate incoming metrics with auto creation & rotation of certificates via CI/CD pipeline
- Automated compile & release creation of repos by small Docker project
- Utilized CD pipeline to automatically rotate DB and Grafana credentials

Leveraged Knowledge in Git, Grafana, InfluxDB, Riemann, Telegraf, Bash

#### Performance Engineer (Mar 2020 - Present)

Optimizing and Benchmarking various solution hosted on Kubernetes

- · Derived optimum configuration of Fluent in EFK stack
- Optimized Cortex performance (Distributed database for Prometheus)

Tooling: K6, Docker, Prometheus, Grafana, Kubernetes, Jaeger

### Software Engineer (Dec 2019 - Feb 2020)

Short lived team meant for evaluating Jaeger for Tracing support

- Architected the Deployment strategy for Jaeger as a Service in an orchestrated environment
- Integrated Jaeger into Observability Stack of SAP Cloud Platform via personal project

Tooling: Cassandra, Jaeger, Helm, Kubernetes, Golang

# DevOps Engineer (May 2019 - April 2020)

- Architected the product to be cloud-native and collaborated with team to ensure that DevOps practices are being followed
- Developed branch agnostic CI/CD pipeline on Jenkins & Github Actions with vulnerabilities checks. Tooling: Github Actions, Jenkins

# Full Stack Developer (May 2019 - Nov 2019)

- Created Backend APIs in NodeJS for various features in a product which helped customers to visualize on-prem landscape
- Did UX enhancements on frontend using SAP UI5 library

#### Linux System Engineer (Aug 2018 - April 2019)

A project dedicated to migrate SAP Netweaver On-Premise systems to GCP

- Migrated 25+ Systems. Team achieved target of 1000 systems by year end
- Automated installation of Netweaver system via Perl script

Tooling: rsync, CloudEndure, Perl, Bash

# 2016 GVC Systems, Noida, India

Intern (May 2016 - June 2016)

Software Developer for IoT based applications and products

- Developed E2E products for customer solving some of their daily problems e.g. Capture Vehicle Number in parking lot, Automatic Door Lock System, Dash Cam streaming video to Cloud.
- Technologies: Docker, MQTT, SpringBoot, Android, Image Recognition, Java
  Python

#### Contact

-

+91 8285 888 886



arpitjindal97@gmail.com



github.com/arpitjindal97 twitter.com/arpitjindal97



linkedin.com/in/arpitjindal97



# **ACHIEVEMENTS & CERTIFICATIONS**

2021

Certified Kubernetes Administrator (July 2021 - July 2024)

2017

Secured 2nd position in Inter College Quiz Competition (Feb 2017)

2015

Awarded 50% Scholarship in all Semesters



# **SKILLS**

- · Kubernetes. Helm
- K6, JMeterPrometheus, Fluent, Jaeger
- Docker
- Grafana, Kibana
- GitOps, IaC
- Cortex, InfluxDB
- · Bash, Golang
- GCP, AWS



#### **EDUCATION**

Jenkins, GH Actions

2018

M.Tech in Software Engineering (CGPA 8.53)

BITS Pilani (Aug 2018 - July 2022)

2015

Bachelor in Computer Applications (CGPA 7.52)

Amity University (July 2015 - June 2018)



# **OPEN-SOURCE CONTRIBUTIONS**

Prometheus

Raised issue & followed through for the fix - Link

• Raspbian Recipes

Network related scripts - Link

Jaeger

Contributed to Helm Charts - Link

Jaeger Deployer

Deploy Multi-tenant Jaeger using K8s - Link

Activities on Github

Various PRs & Issues - Link



# **HOBBIES AND INTEREST**

- Playing Games
- Streaming Netflix
- Irregular GYM
- · Coded this file in Latex
- Listening to Music